okay my name's Drew and we'll be taking
a quick tour of Dropbox which is a
better way of keeping your important
stuff synchronized across your PCS and
what makes Dropbox different is that it
just works meaning that there's no
complicated setup or configuration and
if you're familiar with development
tools Dropbox is kind of like taking
subversion and rsync and making them
easy to use so here we'll walk through a
concrete example and so I just got a new
laptop and I've got some important files
on my desktop that I like to keep
synchronized across both machines means
and to set up Dropbox all you really
have to do is install the application
which I did a moment ago and then link
it to an account so I typed into my
information there and it brings me this
web interface where I can see recent
changes to the files in my Dropbox and I
can actually get the files directly so
in addition to synchronizing files
across PCS Dropbox also securely backs
them up and synchronizes them to the web
so you can click on any of these files
and it does what you'd expect uh in case
you're not at one of your
computers and as far as the window
Windows interface it looks like a normal
Windows folder except for these green
and blue icons indicating whether or not
the file's up to date and Dropbox is
done pulling down all of my stuff and uh
an important idea behind Dropbox is that
it fits into the way you already work
and synchronizes your files continuously
so I can make a change to a document so
like this text
document and I'll hit
save and actually the change will uh
take effect just as quickly as it can be
sent over my internet connection so if I
refresh the page uh it'll indicate the
change and it even extends to another
computer so I have got I've got my
desktop right here and if I open that
file I can make a change on my desktop
and have it reflect on my laptop so I'll
do that on my desktop
here and when I come back to my laptop
you'll notice there's this notification
indicating that the files been changed
and when I reopen the file
uh you'll notice this text has changed
and here's a change for my desktop and
likewise the web interface will
change um in addition to this continuous
sync Behavior Uh Dropbox also archives
past versions of each of each file so
you can click this revisions option and
sort of go back in time so here's the
version we were just looking at and
here's the version we first
saved and and so on and in addition to
revision control there's also some rich
sharing features so one example is this
public folder and every file in your
public folder you just save it there and
it gets uh an internet link associated
with it so I'll do that one more time
you can copy uh any link location of a
file in your public
folder and you can send put this in an I
am window or send it in an email as
opposed to clogging someone's uh email
box with a huge attachment and so it
works with files of any size um in
addition there are shared folders called
works spaces I won't I won't be able to
get to those right during this demo but
um one more thing I want to show you is
that Dropbox is very efficient about the
way it handles changes to files so it
only sends the pieces of files that
change so other tools might do this with
text uh but here we'll do it with a
binary file so there's this
picture and if I make a small change to
the picture so I'll pick this
gross pink color here and change portion
of the image uh it's a little hard to
visualize but digging under the hood I
can show you that Dropbox only sends or
only sends the piece of the file that
changed so this saves over 90% of the
bandwidth as the patch is 10% of the
size of the original file and uh it will
continue to sore these sort of
differential
changes and you can see that what is
transmitted is much smaller than the
original file and you can also see that
these changes are reflected immediately
okay so this makes it feasible to work
with files that are gigabytes in size
even if you have a comparatively slow
internet
connection uh and with that we'll wrap
up and the service is currently in
private beta but if you'd like to check
it out uh please visit get dropbox.com
and you can sign up thanks